bulknutrition.com 2012-10-04

# Bulk Nutrition - Privacy Policy

Web Site Privacy Statement

Effective on: (08/16/2011)

BulkNutrition.com is committed to your privacy. We disclose our information practices below and we agree to notify you of:

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personal identification is collected from you through this web site;
  2. How the information is used;
  3. With whom the information may be shared;
  4. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information;
  5. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under BulkNutrition.com control;
  6. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding these statements, you should contact customer service by email.

At BulkNutrition.com we protect your privacy as if it were our own. We use the information you provide to us for the following purposes only: to process your order(s), to reply to your questions, to provide our newsletters or other correspondence by email and to incorporate your feedback into improvements to our web site. We will not give, sell, or rent your personal information, including email address, or specific account activity to any unaffiliated party for any reason without your prior consent except as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our web site.

Our Secure Ordering.

BulkNutrition.com uses Secured Socket Layer (SSL) technology to ensure the privacy of your personal information. When you make an online purchase, our advanced security technology encrypts and scrambles your personal data (including your name, delivery and e-mail addresses and credit card number) before it is sent to us, making it virtually impossible for anyone other than us (BulkNutrition.com) to read it. To further protect your information, we utilize state of the art back-end systems and restrict employee access to your information. Unless specifically authorized by you, no outside party is able to access or receive any of your personal customer information.

Credit Card Fraud Protection.

All major credit card companies protect cardholders against fraud, subject to a $50 deductible. We will protect you for this $50 portion in the highly unlikely situation that you ever encounter an inappropriate charge involving our company and the credit card company charges you the $50 deductible without offset.

Optional Phone Ordering.

If you are still skeptical about placing your order online, you may place your order over the phone at (484) 668-1581 during customer service hours: Monday through Friday from 8am-6pm ET.

On-line ordering is available to you 24 hours a day, seven days a week.

**Information We Collect.**

We started with the simple belief that customer service is our number one priority. Therefore the customer information we collect is used to enhance our services to you, our customer.

**When you visit our website, we collect non-personal information about your visit.** We collect your IP address, browser type, domain name, and we log the length of time of your visit and the number of times you visit and purchase from us. We assign you a unique internal identifier to help keep track of your future visits. We use this information to gather aggregate demographic information about our visitors, and we use it to personalize the information you see on our website and the emails you receive from us.. 

**Our Web site uses cookies to store information between users' visits to our site and for the duration of the visit, also known as a session.** Cookies are a mechanism to remember information about you when you navigate from one Web page to another. Our Web site uses cookies to hold users' unique session identifiers, allowing our Web server to serve correct information back to the user. Such information includes the user's shopping cart items, or whether you logged in when requesting to view or modify personal information, including your email address, which may have been stored in our database in the past. Disabling or rejecting cookies will prevent you from adding items to the cart and checking out; however, standard browsing on our Web site does not require cookies.

**BulkNutrition.com uses tracking technologies** to send anonymous information about your browsing habits to a third party company. Links in our email communications to recipients are tracked via Web Beacons once you land on our website. Web Beacons appear on our website as 1x1 transparent images which transmit information such as your operating system, browser, resolution, geographical location, products ordered, and order total. This information is used to help our webmasters and marketers understand the behavior of visitors to our website and understand the effectiveness of online and email messages. Your information is submitted anonymously, and no sensitive or personally identifiable information is transmitted.

**When you subscribe to our services we ask for your contact information** (your name and email address). When you sign up for our services we use your name and email address to send you our sales promotions, special product offerings updates and other relevant information. When you submit a product review on our website, you are required to log into your customer account. Your comments, first name, city, and state will be displayed. However, no information that would allow others to contact you will be disclosed. Your information will  be used to allow us to personalize your experience, to help us to communicate with you, and for you to submit product reviews.

Recommend product to a friend.

The information collected (friend's name and email address) is used to send emails to the friend letting them know about the product that the user recommends.

**If you place an online order, our secure order form requests contact, billing, and financial information** (such as your credit card numbers for purchases). Contact information from the order form (email address, name, billing and shipping address, and phone number) is used to send orders and information about our company to you. Your contact information, including email address, is also used to contact you should we have questions regarding your order or should we need to notify you of the status of your order. You can choose not to receive email from us, as described in the opt-out section below. The credit card information we collect is used to bill you for products you purchase, and if you provide prior consent, this information may also be shared with a third-party partner. For your convenience, your information including credit card and order history is stored on a secure server that allows you to reorder by entering your email address and password. You may also place an autoship order, when we enable such technology, that will allow you to receive products on a regular basis without the need to reenter that order every time. If you select the autoship option, you may cancel the recurring order at anytime on BulkNutrition.com by sending an email to customer service or calling (484) 668-1581.

We have several types of third-party relationships.

  1. We use third-party intermediaries. When you purchase from us, we send your encrypted credit card information, name, and billing address, over a secure server connection, to credit card companies for verification and to authorize your purchase.
  2. We use outside shipping companies to fulfill orders. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information, including email address, for any other purposes.
  3. We may provide certain third party offers for your consideration. Should you choose to place an order with one of these partners, in some cases we will share certain information, including email address, necessary to facilitate your transaction with them. We will always ask for your consent prior to sharing your information with anyone other than those specifically explained in our policies.
  4. We handle the sending of order related and customer service related messages internally, as well as advertising related emails. It is our policy that our service providers do not retain nor use your personal information, including your email address for any other purpose except to provide the service on our behalf.
  5. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 

**We occasionally run online surveys** and we ask visitors for contact information (such as email address) and demographic information (such as zip code, age, or income level). We use contact data from our surveys to send users information about our companies. You may opt-out of the survey and also opt-out of any future mailings at various times. The demographic information is used to learn more about the types of people who visit our site. This information is not shared with any third parties currently. We reserve the right to share this information with third parties in the future in an aggregated format that would not disclose any personally identifiable information.

Opt-Out.

If you decide that you would like to opt-out of receiving newsletters from us, our emails provide you with the opportunity to stop receiving these communications. Simply click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email.

Links.

This site contains links to other sites. BulkNutrition.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

When You Send Email to our Customer Service Department.

We read every message and try to reply promptly. The information you send us is used to respond directly to your questions and comments. We also keep your email correspondence on file as needed so that we may better serve you should you have additional questions. Your personal information is shared with third parties (such as manufacturers) to facilitate improvements in products or services and deliver products and orders.

How We Notify You of Changes to our Privacy Policy.

Whenever we change our privacy policy, we will post a notice on our website indicating that a new version is available. 

Contacting the Web Site.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact customer service.
